<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.yewjin.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.yewjin.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2024-02-25T21:30:04+00:00</updated><id>https://www.yewjin.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Yew Jin</title><subtitle>About Yew Jin. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2024/2024-02-25-ethereum-thesis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2024-02-25T21:30:04+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-25T21:30:04+00:00</updated><id>https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2024/2024-02-25-ethereum-thesis</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2024/2024-02-25-ethereum-thesis/"><![CDATA[<p>Ethereum is the “silver” of the cryptocurrency world behind Bitcoin, which firmly anchors itself to Digital Gold and primarily as a store of value. While I have both cryptocurrencies in my portfolio, Ethereum is between the both of them, the stronger conviction investment for me. Here’s why.</p>

<h2 id="blockchains-are-not-databases-theyre-full-fledged-computers---chris-dixon-read-write-own">“Blockchains are not databases; they’re full-fledged computers.” - Chris Dixon, Read Write Own</h2>

<p>Forget the old notion of blockchains as static ledgers. Ethereum has shattered this perception by proving itself as a dynamic, programmable computer. This is a virtual computing platform that has ownership as a core design principle; “logging-in” doesn’t mean the same thing in Web3 as it does in Web2. This distinction is crucial; Ethereum provides a foundation for innovations that could reshape the internet as we know it.</p>

<p>The concept of “programmable money” is where I see the real game-changer. Ethereum allows for creating smart contracts, which are essentially programs that execute financial transactions under certain conditions. However, Ethereum hasn’t yet found its “iPhone moment” — that breakthrough application that makes its value obvious to everyone. We’ve seen sparks of interest with NFTs and DeFi, but these haven’t quite bridged the gap to mainstream adoption.</p>

<h2 id="most-current-ai-systems-have-no-economic-model-for-creators---chris-dixon-read-write-own">“Most current AI systems have no economic model for creators.” - Chris Dixon, Read Write Own</h2>

<p>The intersection of generative AI and Ethereum presents a compelling narrative. With Ethereum, there’s potential to create a new economic model for AI, where creators are compensated through smart contracts, and AI-generated content and services are traded on a decentralized marketplace. This could pave the way for fairer, more transparent economic systems for digital content and services. Moreover, as AI continues to evolve, integrating with Ethereum could ensure that the creators and developers behind AI innovations are directly rewarded for their contributions, fostering a more sustainable ecosystem for digital innovation.</p>

<p>I am cautiously optimistic, but the success of Ethereum feels like a matter of “when” rather than “if.” I’m betting it’s Gen AI-related.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Estimating the Probability of Not Proposing an Ethereum Block</title><link href="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2024/eth-validator-block-probability/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Estimating the Probability of Not Proposing an Ethereum Block" /><published>2024-01-27T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-27T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2024/eth-validator-block-probability</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2024/eth-validator-block-probability/"><![CDATA[<p>As an Ethereum staker, one of the key aspects of participation in the network is decentralization … OK … nevermind it’s the opportunity to propose a block and hope for winning the block lottery. The probability of getting this chance, however, depends on several factors, most notably the total number of validators in the network and the number of validators you control. Here’s how to calculate the probability of not proposing a block over different time periods - an hour, a day, a week, or even a month. Because, admit it, you are only asking this question after not getting a block proposal for that long and you are asking: “WHAT ARE THE ODDS?!”</p>

<p>The Ethereum PoS protocol, specifically in the context of block validation, operates with discrete time units called slots. A new block is proposed in each slot by a randomly selected validator. The probability of a specific validator being chosen for any given slot is inversely proportional to the total number of validators.</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Total Number of Validators (N):</strong> The entire set of validators staking ETH in the network. You can use <a href="https://www.validatorqueue.com/">validatorqueue.com</a> but as of Jan 27 2024, it’s around 905,000.</li>
  <li><strong>Your Validators (V):</strong> The number of validators under your control.</li>
  <li><strong>Time Period (T):</strong> The duration for which you want to calculate the probability, measured in slots. (Note: The Ethereum network typically operates with a slot time of 12 seconds.)</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="calculating-the-probability">Calculating the Probability</h3>

<p>The probability of not proposing a block in a single slot, for a user with V validators, is calculated as follows:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>Probability (Single Slot) = 1 - (V / N)
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>To extend this to a specific time period, T slots, the formula becomes:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>Probability (T Slots) = (1 - (V / N))^T
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Handy number of slots in various time periods</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>For One Hour:</strong> With T = 300 slots (assuming 12 seconds per slot).</li>
  <li><strong>For One Day:</strong> T = 7,200 slots.</li>
  <li><strong>For One Week:</strong> T = 50,400 slots.</li>
  <li><strong>For One Month:</strong> Approximating a month as 30 days, T = 216,000 slots.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="probabilities-for-1-validator">Probabilities for 1 Validator</h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Probability of not proposing a block in one slot:</strong> \(1 - \frac{1}{905,000}\)</li>
  <li><strong>One Hour (300 slots):</strong> \(\left( 1 - \frac{1}{905,000} \right)^{300}\)</li>
  <li><strong>One Day (7,200 slots):</strong> \(\left( 1 - \frac{1}{905,000} \right)^{7200}\)</li>
  <li><strong>One Week (50,400 slots):</strong> \(\left( 1 - \frac{1}{905,000} \right)^{50400}\)</li>
  <li><strong>One Month (approx. 30 days, 216,000 slots):</strong> \(\left( 1 - \frac{1}{905,000} \right)^{216000}\)</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="summary">Summary</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in one hour:</strong> Approximately 99.97%</li>
  <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in one day:</strong> Approximately 99.21%</li>
  <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in one week:</strong> Approximately 94.58%</li>
  <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in one month:</strong> Approximately 78.75%</li>
  <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in 3 months:</strong> Approximately 48.84%</li>
  <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in 6 months:</strong> Approximately 23.86%</li>
  <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in 1 year:</strong> Approximately 5.69%</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="probabilities-for-100-validators">Probabilities for 100 Validators</h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Probability of not proposing a block in one slot (for any of the 100 validators):</strong> \(1 - \frac{100}{905,000}\)</li>
  <li><strong>One Hour (300 slots):</strong> \(\left( 1 - \frac{100}{905,000} \right)^{300}\)</li>
  <li><strong>One Day (7,200 slots):</strong> \(\left( 1 - \frac{100}{905,000} \right)^{7200}\)</li>
  <li><strong>One Week (50,400 slots):</strong> \(\left( 1 - \frac{100}{905,000} \right)^{50400}\)</li>
  <li><strong>One Month (approx. 30 days, 216,000 slots):</strong> \(\left( 1 - \frac{100}{905,000} \right)^{216000}\)</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="summary-1">Summary</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in one hour:</strong> Approximately 96.74%</li>
  <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in one day:</strong> Approximately 45.10%</li>
  <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in one week:</strong> Approximately 0.38%</li>
  <li><strong>Chance of not proposing a block in one month:</strong> Practically 0% (very close to zero)</li>
</ul>

<p>Finally, this is a simple model yada yada (technically you should look at effective validator balances), if you want to see the latest’s statistics on block proposal frequency, see <a href="https://luckystaker.com/home/">LuckyStaker.com</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[When your solo staking setup isn't proposing, you are asking "WHAT ARE THE ODDS?!"]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nailed that one</title><link href="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2024/nailed-that-one/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nailed that one" /><published>2024-01-20T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-20T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2024/nailed-that-one</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2024/nailed-that-one/"><![CDATA[<p>In other words, $10K worth of Bitcoins bought today could be valued at $1M (or zero dollars) in only just a tew years.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Yew Jin, July 2014, <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1-3R10vhbe5GgBeREda3nAXtlT5YpwEviBao340H3tgM/edit?usp=sharing">Bitcoin investment thesis</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Average price ~ July 2014: $531.13</p>

<figure>

  <picture>
    
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/bitcoin-2014-2023-480.webp" />
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/bitcoin-2014-2023-800.webp" />
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/bitcoin-2014-2023-1400.webp" />
    

    <!-- Fallback to the original file -->
    <img src="/assets/img/bitcoin-2014-2023.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();" />

  </picture>

</figure>

<p>Gotta say I kinda of nailed that one.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You don't care, but I'm surprised at myself...]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">This is not fine fire</title><link href="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2023/this-is-not-fine-fire/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This is not fine fire" /><published>2023-10-01T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-01T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2023/this-is-not-fine-fire</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2023/this-is-not-fine-fire/"><![CDATA[<figure>

  <picture>
    
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/this-is-not-fine-fire-480.webp" />
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/this-is-not-fine-fire-800.webp" />
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/this-is-not-fine-fire-1400.webp" />
    

    <!-- Fallback to the original file -->
    <img src="/assets/img/this-is-not-fine-fire.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();" />

  </picture>

</figure>

<p>DALLE-3 and its text understanding capabilities are unreal y’all.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[DALLE-3 is 🔥]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Podcast for You! And You! And You!</title><link href="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2023/a-podcast-just-for-you/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Podcast for You! And You! And You!" /><published>2023-07-29T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-29T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2023/a-podcast-just-for-you</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2023/a-podcast-just-for-you/"><![CDATA[<p>Imagine starting your day with a tailored podcast, containing summarized stories from various newspapers and websites that you care about. With advances in LLMs and Text-to-Speech, it is now possible to automate this process.</p>

<p>Here are sample podcasts created for a “tech user in the Bay Area” on July 29, 2023.</p>

<h2 id="hacker-news">Hacker News</h2>
<figure>

  <audio src="/assets/mp3/hacker_news_podcast_jul_27_23.mp3" controls="" />

</figure>

<p><a href="/assets/txt/hacker_news_podcast_jul_27_23.txt" target="_blank">Download the transcript for the hacker news sample podcast</a></p>

<figure>

  <picture>
    
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/hacker_news_page_270723-480.webp" />
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/hacker_news_page_270723-800.webp" />
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/hacker_news_page_270723-1400.webp" />
    

    <!-- Fallback to the original file -->
    <img src="/assets/img/hacker_news_page_270723.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();" />

  </picture>

</figure>

<h2 id="new-york-times">New York Times</h2>
<figure>

  <audio src="/assets/mp3/nytimes-podcast-290723.mp3" controls="" />

</figure>

<p><a href="/assets/txt/nytimes-podcast-transcript-290723.txt" target="_blank">Download the transcript for the nytimes sample podcast</a></p>

<figure>

  <picture>
    
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/nytimes-290723-480.webp" />
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/nytimes-290723-800.webp" />
    <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/nytimes-290723-1400.webp" />
    

    <!-- Fallback to the original file -->
    <img src="/assets/img/nytimes-290723.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();" />

  </picture>

</figure>

<p>By leveraging AI technologies like OpenAI’s GPT-4 for content curation and summarization, and ElevenLabs’ text-to-speech for converting the script into a podcast, we can automate the process of creating personalized podcasts. It’s an exciting time to explore the possibilities of AI in customizing and enhancing our consumption of online content.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[One small step for how LLMs are going to change your world]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How LLM, Generative AI Image/Video, and Blockchain will Change the World in the Next 3 Years</title><link href="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2023/llm/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How LLM, Generative AI Image/Video, and Blockchain will Change the World in the Next 3 Years" /><published>2023-01-16T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-16T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2023/llm</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2023/llm/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="how-llm-generative-ai-and-blockchain-are-going-to-change-the-world-in-the-next-3-years">How LLM, Generative AI, and Blockchain are Going to Change the World in the Next 3 Years</h1>

<p>It’s often said that the world changes more in the next 10 years than it has in the last 10 years. This rings especially true with the rapid development of technology like LLM (Large Language Models), Generative AI image/video generation, and blockchain. In the next three years, these technologies are likely to change the world more than it has in the past 10 years.</p>

<p>However, these technologies aren’t made equally. They often work together to create a larger impact on the world, with each technology reinforcing the positive effects of another. They also often have a negative side, making the effects of the other technologies worse.</p>

<p>In this post, we’ll discuss the potential impact of these technologies, as well as their potential shortcomings. We’ll focus on LLMs, generative AI image/video generation, and blockchain.</p>

<h2 id="llms-large-language-models">LLMs (Large Language Models)</h2>

<p>Steve Jobs famously said that the computer is a “bicycle for the mind”–a tool to make humans more efficient in writing. LLMs, or Large Language Models, are the acceleration of the bicycle for the mind. LLMs allow humans to write more quickly and eloquently than ever before by relying on AI assistance.</p>

<p>The best writing won’t be entirely written by AI, however. It’ll be a collaboration between human and AI, with humans relying on AI to help them write better and faster. But this collaboration has its drawbacks, like the potential for cheating, and more effective misinformation.</p>

<h3 id="potential-for-cheating">Potential for Cheating</h3>

<p>Cheating will be easier than ever before with LLMs. Students will be able to rely on LLMs to help them quickly write essays for their homework or school assignments. Similarly, students may be able to use LLMs to help them write exams and homework.</p>

<p>What happens when LLMs become too effective at writing? It’ll be harder to find the best writers, and it’ll be harder to distinguish between good and bad writers. LLMs that can write will also make it easier to write quality text quickly, making it harder to detect cheating even when a student uses an LLM to help them write.</p>

<h3 id="more-effective-misinformation">More Effective Misinformation</h3>

<p>Misinformation is information that’s false, but usually presented in a manner that appears true to the uninformed reader. Those who are misinformed are often aware that the information is false, but deliberately present it as if it’s true. This can cause people to believe the information and act on it, even if it’s wrong.</p>

<p>For example, a politician may want to spread false information about their opponent to convince people that their opponent is dishonest. In this scenario, it’s likely that the politician is aware that the information is false, but will spread it anyway because it benefits them.</p>

<p>Misinformation has always been a problem. Misinformation has never been more effective or easy to create than it is now, with the help of writing AI.</p>

<p>For example, a politician may use writing AI to write text that they can use to mislead the public. This text will be written in a way that sounds accurate and believable to the reader, making it harder to disprove or refute.</p>

<h2 id="generative-ai-art">Generative AI Art</h2>

<p>Generative AI image generation is advancing rapidly, and generative AI video generation is inevitable. With these technologies, we will have higher quality images and videos, as well as more efficient ways to create content. Still, many people will rely on AI to create content, and this is where AI’s relentless ability to scale and produce a large amount of information will overwhelm our current systems. For example, AI models are currently being used to create art that’s similar to a specific artist’s style, or an individual person’s style.</p>

<p>This may sound like fiction, but it’s actually happening now. Tools like DALL-E 2, Stable Diffusion, Midjourney, etc. showed that AI models are able to create images that are similar to an individual artist’s style, or an individual person’s style. These models can also create art that’s similar to a specific artist’s style, or an individual person’s style.</p>

<h2 id="what-systems-are-being-overwhelmed">What Systems are Being Overwhelmed?</h2>

<p>Still, many people will rely on AI to create content, and this is where AI’s relentless ability to scale and produce a large amount of information will overwhelm our current systems.</p>

<p>The cultural and economic systems are likely to be particularly affected. The debate around AI art stealing from existing artists is analogous to human artists being inspired by works of art that they see and learn from. This raises the question of whether this type of “standing on the shoulders of giants” works when AI does it.</p>

<p>The current digital copyright systems are also likely to be overwhelmed. Digital media can easily be copied and redistributed, making it more difficult to control the spread of digital media. This can lead to the devaluation of original artwork and the potential for more legal disputes over the ownership of digital media.</p>

<h3 id="the-increasing-need-for-scalable-digital-ownership">The Increasing Need for Scalable Digital Ownership</h3>

<p>As LLMs and generative AI become more advanced, the need for scalable digital ownership will become increasingly critical. Blockchain technology, via Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs), provides a viable solution, as it allows digital content to be securely tracked and buy and sold. This would help protect original creators from losing out on potential profits from their artwork, and would also reduce the amount of legal disputes over the ownership of digital media.</p>

<p>NFTs provides a way to prove ownership and authorship of digital content, allowing creators to monetize their work. This can also help reduce the potential for cheating and misinformation, as the provenance of content can be verified. Additionally, this could help reduce the amount of digital theft since digital media can be tracked and traced to its original owner. Finally, it could also lead to new economic models, as digital content can be securely bought, sold, and traded with ease.</p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>In the next three years, the world is likely to change more than it has in the past 10 years due to the rapid development of LLMs, generative AI, and blockchain. LLMs allow humans to write more quickly and eloquently, while generative AI image and video generation is likely to improve the quality of digital media. Blockchains and NFTs will help reduce digital theft and create a secure way of proving digital ownership. All of these technologies are likely to overwhelm our current systems, leading to a cultural and economic revolution where these technologies work together to create a new ecosystem to support the industry.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[LLM, Generative AI Art, and Blockchain are going to change the world]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning as a Web3 creator</title><link href="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2022/web3-creator/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning as a Web3 creator" /><published>2022-12-18T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-18T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2022/web3-creator</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2022/web3-creator/"><![CDATA[<p>I have been looking for ways to learn more about Web3 and content creating. And I recently stumbled upon a great platform called <a href="https://showtime.xyz">showtime.xyz</a>, which facilitates creators to upload and showcase their NFTs, digital and crypto art.</p>

<p>With showtime.xyz, I have found a way to not only learn more about Web3, but also to use AI artwork and mint NFTs to do it. As a bonus, I am able to find an excuse to create AI art.</p>

<p>Showtime.xyz mints NFTs on Polygon mainnet and gives them to users for free.</p>

<p>To make the most of the platform, I have been thinking about how to organize my artwork so that it is attractive and also creates buzz. I have also created token-gated access to new content so that there is incentive for people to engage with my work. Check out <a href="https://showtime.xyz/yewjin">showtime.xyz/yewjin</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learning by doing]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Crypto Thoughts</title><link href="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2022/crypto-thoughts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Crypto Thoughts" /><published>2022-09-18T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-18T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2022/crypto-thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2022/crypto-thoughts/"><![CDATA[<p>As I am writing this blog post #cryptocrash is tredning on Twitter. ETH is at $1300 and BTC is at $18,800. This isn’t looking good to say the least, but I figure I will write down my thesis as a matter of financial discipline.</p>

<ul>
  <li>ETH. Long-term bullish. Short-term confused.</li>
  <li>BTC. Store of value.</li>
  <li>APE. Yuga Labs ecosystem. Ugh on staking for ApeCoin.</li>
  <li>NFTs - buy the bluechips. Leave it along.
    <ul>
      <li>Yuga Labs: BAYC, Punks, Otherside, MAYC, BAKC. In that order.</li>
      <li>Moonbirds</li>
      <li>Nouns?</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As I am writing this blog post #cryptocrash is tredning on Twitter. ETH is at $1300 and BTC is at $18,800. This isn’t looking good to say the least, but I figure I will write down my thesis as a matter of financial discipline.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Crypto Cyberops</title><link href="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2022/crypto-cyberops/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Crypto Cyberops" /><published>2022-08-04T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-04T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2022/crypto-cyberops</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2022/crypto-cyberops/"><![CDATA[<p>Here’s my multifactor way to store your crypto safely with a break glass scenario for emergencies:</p>

<p>Use <a href="https://gnosis-safe.io/">Gnosis Safe</a> to manage a multi-sig wallet secured by multiple hardware wallets like those from <a href="https://www.ledger.com/">Ledger</a>, <a href="https://gridplus.io/products/grid-lattice1">Grid+ Lattice1</a>, and <a href="https://trezor.io/">Trezor</a>.</p>

<p>Next, secure your hardware wallets with the following protocol:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Use steel plates/capsules to protect from physical events and degradation over time.</li>
  <li>Utilize <a href="https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0039.mediawiki#from-mnemonic-to-seed">BIP39 passphrase</a> to require a password on top of the seed phrase.</li>
  <li>Shamir’s secret sharing to shard seed phrases to store steel plates/capsules in multiple locations, and prevents any single discovery to be an issue like <a href="https://github.com/iancoleman/shamir39">Shamir39</a></li>
</ol>

<p>i.e., multisig wallet with the hardware wallets access to multiple factors with password/pins, and recovery of hardware wallets in case of hardware failure requires knowledge (BIP39 passphrase) on top of just physically recovering multiple seeds. The hardware wallets are somewhat optional but it can be a security risk itself to try and recover your private keys often.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing this down because the other liability is forgetting the protocol]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nicotinamide Mononucleotide (NMN)–The NAD+ Precursor That May Help Combat Aging and Disease</title><link href="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2022/nmn/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nicotinamide Mononucleotide (NMN)–The NAD+ Precursor That May Help Combat Aging and Disease" /><published>2022-07-18T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-18T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2022/nmn</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yewjin.com/blog/2022/nmn/"><![CDATA[<p>As we age, our cells gradually become less efficient at converting food into energy. This process, known as cellular senescence, is a major contributor to the aging process. But what if there were a way to help cells stay young and healthy for longer?</p>

<p><a href="https://www.foundmyfitness.com/topics/nicotinamide-mononucleotide">Nicotinamide mononucleotide (NMN)</a> is a compound that has shown promise in treating aging and age-related diseases. NMN is an intermediate compound in the NAD+ salvage pathway, the recycling of nicotinamide into NAD+. NAD+ levels decrease with age and may in part drive the aging process and the development of age-related diseases. Boosting NAD+ levels through precursors has proven to have therapeutic potential in treating aging and age-related diseases across multiple animal models. NMN supplements are readily available, and studies in animal models have shown that NMN can help reverse age-related cellular decline and improve cognitive function.</p>

<p>In a study involving diet-induced diabetic mice, injection of 500 milligrams per kilogram of body weight (mg/kg/bw) of nicotinamide mononucleotide administered for seven days enhanced insulin sensitivity and improved glucose intolerance compared to that observed among mice not given nicotinamide mononucleotide. Additionally, the mice that were fed nicotinamide mononucleotide had improved skeletal muscle mitochondrial function, increased energy expenditure, increased bone density, and decreased insulin resistance in a dose-dependent manner.</p>

<p>Rats that were injected with 500 mg/kg/bw of nicotinamide mononucleotide every day for 10 days demonstrated sustained improvement in cognitive function as well as an attenuation of neuronal cell death. These data suggest that nicotinamide mononucleotide has potential as a therapy for aging and age-related diseases. However, the safety and efficacy of NMN supplementation in humans remain unknown.</p>

<p>The first human clinical trial of NMN is now underway, and early results are promising. If NMN is found to be safe and effective in humans, it could be a major breakthrough in the fight against aging and age-related diseases.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A promising compound for aging and age-related diseases]]></summary></entry></feed>